AMAO ADEYINKA OLUWATOSIN

5 Temidire Street, Ososami, Ibadan, Oyo State. 08067868191, 08076826862, amaoyinka1@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a meticulous, proactive, and dynamic sales and warehouse manager with over 5 years of Cognate experience. I am an exceptional leader with a track record of developing business and sales Methodologies that boost market growth, ensuring consistent monitoring of goods received, storage and distribution operations, product handlings and inventories record, analyzing location market trends, and discovering new opportunities for business expansion. Based on my experience, I have developed proficiency in warehouse management, sales management, start-up of new business outlets, marketing strategies, customer relation techniques, safety and security management, training development, and team management.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Warehouse management
- ➤ Business start-up
- Marketing
- Analytical
- Presentation

- ➤ Sales Management
- ➤ Customer relation
- Purchasing and supply
- ➤ Excellent communication
- ➤ Teamwork
- ➤ Training and Development
- Ability to work under pressure

DATE

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

ALERZO LIMITED.

Warehouse Manager.

Till Date

Sep,2022

B2B logistic company connecting retailers in emerging markets directly to consumer goods brands on a mission to bridge the gap between retailers and FMCG. Enable retailers to order goods when they need it and provide supply chain, logistics and warehouse facilities, retail-as-a-service, and real-time free delivery.

- ➤ Supervise daily warehouse activities, including quality assurance, inventory control, space management, logistics, floor productivity, shipping, and customer service.
- ➤ Schedule and oversee warehouse team and manage the flow and quality of work to maximize efficiency and minimize overtime.
- ➤ Inspect equipment, tools, and machinery regularly, and oversee general maintenance when necessary.
- ➤ Meet regularly with warehouse leads to analyse productivity and develop actionable plans for loss prevention.
- ➤ Oversee and manage logistics for transporting products to customers and company



facilities, communicating with drivers and air partners to ensure efficient delivery of packages.

Warehouse Supervisor.

Mar,2022

Sep,2022

- ▶ Plan, organize, supervise and participate in daily warehouse operation and activities, including the receipt, documentation, storage, safety and distribution of equipment and supplies and maintenance of inventory.
- ➤ Train, supervise and evaluate the performance of assigned warehouse employees; assign workloads to warehouse workers.
- ➤ Receive, unpack, pack, load, issue, store and deliver materials, textbooks, supplies or equipment; complete packing slips for shipments as assigned.
- ➤ Route, schedule, pack and prepare orders for delivery; load vehicles; schedule and oversee deliveries and pick-ups.
- Supervise the processing of requisitions and requests to invoice for reimbursements of warehouse codes; complete requisitions for needed materials to assure adequate stock levels.
- Prepare and maintain a variety of records and logs and prepare reports as required; maintain inventory of items in the warehouse; file records as required; supervise the assembly of inventory printouts and catalogs as required.
- Operate and demonstrate use of specialized warehouse equipment as necessary; assure proper and routine maintenance and servicing of warehouse vehicles and equipment.

Warehouse Manager

Feb 2021 - Feb.2022

Ejide Nigeria Limited (Major Distributors - FMCG)

Responsibilities

- ➤ Maintain and facilitate the receiving, storage, and distribution of goods and products.
- ➤ Ensure product handling and maintenance of inventory records by conducting physical counts and reconciling them with the data storage system.
- ➤ Periodic spot checks and stock control system up to date and plan future capacity requirements.
- ➤ Supervising and checking of waybills of every product received in tonnes
- ➤ Ensure proper arrangement and physical condition of the warehouse with adherence to set SOPS.
- ➤ Implementation of standard health, safety, hygiene, and security of lives and properties in the warehouse.
- ➤ Ensure stock received is arranged in accordance with the best practice of FIFO.
- ➤ Motivation and encouragement of the sales team within the workforce to ensure productivity and efficiency.
- ➤ Documentation and keeping of warehouse stock balance both daily and weekly.
- ➤ Ensure set up layout and efficient space utilization.
- ➤ Training of staff and performance monitoring.
- ➤ Liaise with clients and suppliers on the products and goods received.



Sales Manager Nov.2017 -

Jan.2021

Ejide Nigeria Limited (Major Distributors- FMCG)

Responsibilities

➤ Ensured proper coordination of direct sales, client service, and effective strategies to drive sales growth.

- ➤ Maintained excellent customer service and growing company revenue.
- ➤ Achieved and exceed the assigned sales target within the given time.
- ➤ Ensured product improvements or new products by remaining current on industry trends, market activities, and competitors.
- ➤ Maintained accurate records of the total number of sales made on daily basis, with potential and existing customers.
- ➤ Maintained an efficient distribution network and routine for timely deliveries of products to customers.
- ➤ Scheduled meetings and presentations with prospective customers.
- ➤ Determined monthly and gross profit with the implementation of marketing strategies.
- ➤ Ensured a continuous development of business climate, applications, and competition to define the geographical area.
- ➤ Assessment of individual performance in my team through observation, measurement and suggest corrective actions needed.
- ➤ Training and monitoring of sales team to meet and exceed sales goals.

Key Achievement

- ➤ Start-up of new retail outlet at Abuja as sales manager.
- > Start-up of new retail outlet in Saki, Oyo State as warehouse manager.
- ➤ Increased the sales of golden penny product with huge market turnover within the shortest period.
- ➤ Merchandizing market penetration of golden penny product within the shortest period.

Sales Merchandiser (Golden penny)

March — October

2017

Flour mills of Nigeria, life - camp Jabi Abuja

Responsibilities

- ➤ Responsible for market visibility, availability, and penetration in the open market and retail stores.
- ➤ Maintained primary and secondary sales.
- ➤ Organized product promotion and advertising campaigns.
- ➤ Supplied goods to the various stores in Abuja metropolis e.g Dutse market, kubwa

market, Gwagwalada market, and wuse market.

- ➤ Retailed business development and sales control.
- ➤ Liaised with the customers on market price, discount, and product availability.
- ➤ Prepared daily and weekly sales reports.

Inspection Officer

April 2015- March 2016

Ministry of Investment, Commerce &Industry, Uyo, Akwa Ibom State.

National Youth Service Corps

Responsibilities

- ➤ Inspection of Peacock Paint Limited, Ikot Ekan, Etinan, Akwa Ibom State
- ➤ Supervision of Palm Oil Plantation, Eastern Obolo, Akwa Ibom.
- ➤ Participation in Akwa Ibom Council of Micro, Small, and Medium Enterprises (MSME), under the Industry Directorate.
- ➤ Supervision team for the renovation of technical college, Uyo, Akwa Ibom

EDUCATION:

➤ Chartered Institute of Customer Relationship Management.	2016
Chartered PGD in Customer Relationship Management	
➤ University of Abuja, Gwagwalada, FCT Abuja.	2014
BSc Business Administration,	
➤ Best Legacy College of Education, Ogbomosho, Oyo State.	2008
Interim Joint and Matriculation Board (IJMB), Grade 10 point	
➤ Best Legacy International School, Ogbomosho, Oyo State	2006
➤ Senior School Certificate Examination	
➤ Baptist High School, Ogbomosho, Oyo State.	2003
➤ Junior Secondary School Certificate	
➤ Ife Oluwa Nursery and Primary School, Ogbomosho	2000
First School leaving Certificate.	

PUBLICATION:

➤ B.sc Research Project: Effect of Environmental Factors on Marketing Activities in Nigeria.

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIP:

- ➤ Chartered Institute of Customer Relationship Management (ACICRM)
- ➤ Nigerian Institute of Management (NIM) Graduate Member.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE:

➤ Electoral Secretary
Federation of Oyo State Students Union, Uniabuja Chapter

2013

➤ General Secretary,



Federation of Ogbomoso Students Union, Uniabuja Chapter	2013
➤ President	
Federation of Ogbomoso Students Union, Uniabuja Chapter	2014
➤ Speaker	
Federation of Ogbomoso Students Union, National Council	2014
➤ General Secretary	
Mountain of Fire and Miracles Ministries Corpers Fellowship, Uyo	2016
National Youth Service Corps, Letter of Commendation	
For the Construction of Municipal Park/Bus Stop constructed	
by me at Idongesit Nkange Secretariat, Uyo, Akwa Ibom State.	2016
 Uyo Capital City Development Authority 	
Letter of Recommendation	2016

PERSONAL DATA:

Sex: Male

Marital Status: Married

Nationality: Nigerian

Languages: English and Yoruba

HOBBIES / INTEREST: Reading, Travelling and Meeting people

REFEREES:

Referees will be furnished on request.